In the last lecture, I introduced you to Gatsbyjs
Son derste seni Gatsbyjs'le tantrdm
and I called it an amazing project,
ve buna inanlmaz bir
it is.
proje dedim, yle.
If that was amazing,
Bu harika olsayd,
react native was just mind blowing.
yerli tepki sadece fleme oldu.
React native, if you google for it you'll find the official page on
Yerel tepki, bunun iin google eer github resmi
github is another project created by Facebook. React native essentially is react
sayfas Facebook tarafndan oluturulan baka bir proje bulacaksnz. Yerel olarak tepki gsterme tepki veriyor ancak
but for mobile apps
mobil uygulamalar iin ve bununla
and with that, I mean native apps, native iOS s or Android apps. With reactjs taught in this course,
birlikte, yerel uygulamalar, yerel iOS'lar veya Android uygulamalarn kastediyorum. Bu derste retilen tepkiler ile tabii ki javascript ile web
you of course learned how to build web apps with javascript,
uygulamalarn nasl oluturacanz rendiniz, doal olarak tepki gstererek, javascript
with react native,
kullann ve
you use javascript and react and another library, react native to build mobile apps. You still write
baka bir ktphane kullanyorsunuz, mobil uygulamalar oluturmak iin yerel olarak tepki veriyorsunuz. Hala javascript kodu yazyorsunuz, ancak yerel tepkiler
javascript code
iOS veya
but then react native will compile that to code that runs on iOS or Android devices,
Android cihazlarda altrlan kodlar derlemek iin tepki gstererek, bu yap
it does so by exposing some building blocks to you like this view component which is your alternative
bileenini size bir div seeneiniz olan bu grnm bileeni gibi
to a div.
gstererek yapyor.
Divs only work in web browsers of course,
Div'ler sadece web tarayclarnda
now the view behind the scenes is an element, an element running on iOS or Android.
alrlar, imdi sahnelerin arkasndaki grnm iOS veya Android'de alan bir elementtir.
That's the idea behind react native,
Yerel olarak tepki vermenin ardndaki
you write native code but with javascript that gets compiled and with the same react logic you learned
fikir budur, yerel kod yazarsnz ancak derlenmi olan javascript ve bu kodda rendiiniz ayn
in this code.
tepki mantyla.
So you still need to learn some new things when diving into react native because of all these new components
Bu nedenle, tm bu yeni bileenler ve deimekte olan dier eyler nedeniyle yerel tepkilere dalmak
and some other things that change but it's still extremely simple to get started.
iin baz yeni eyler renmeniz gerekiyor, ancak yine de balamak iin son derece basit.
There even is a create react app alternative for react native,
Hatta tepki yerel oluturmak iin bir tepki oluturmak alternatif,
it's called create react native app, so very close to the name I guess.
hatta yerel uygulama tepki oluturmak denir, bu yzden tahmin ediyorum ismine ok yakn.
Definitely feel free to dive into react native, dive into docs, use that create react native app too
Yerel olarak tepki vermek, doktorlara dalmaktan ekinmeyin, yerel uygulamalara da tepki vermek iin
and feel free to take your react knowledge to start building native apps with it,
kullann ve bununla birlikte yerel uygulamalar oluturmaya balamak iin tepki bilginizi almaktan ekinmeyin, baz
it takes some adjustments, it takes some new things to learn but it's an amazing opportunity to build
ayarlamalar gerektirir, renmesi gereken yeni eyler alr ancak Sadece web uygulamalar deil gerek
real native apps and not just web apps.
yerel uygulamalar oluturmak iin harika bir frsat.
Now that's not necessarily better
imdi bu daha
but if you want to get into native app development, with that you've got a chance of doing so without
iyi olmayabilir, ancak yerel uygulama gelitirmeye gemek istiyorsanz, Android veya Swift
learning Android or Swift Objective-C first.
Objective-C'yi renmeden bunu yapma ansnz olur.